# Ashwin Ramkumar

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **Details**

London, N6G 4M3 Canada +1 2265031612

adiramash@gmail.com

#### Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashwin -ramkumar-176428b0/ https://github.com/ashwinr63

#### **Skills**

Linux

PHP

HTML & CSS

Node.js

JavaScript

SQL

Python

Git

Java

React

Firebase

Adobe Creative Cloud

### **Profile**

Software Engineer with 3+ years of Work experience in the industry. Experienced in bringing forth ability in Design, Development, Testing and Delivering Projects, Applications. Able to effectively self-manage during independent project, as well as collaborate in a team setting. Worked in Various SDLC models ranging from Agile, Waterfall where the opportunity to work as Web Designer and Developer was also proven.

## **Employment History**

#### Software Engineer, Cognizant Technology Solutions, Coimbatore

AUGUST 2018 — JANUARY 2020

- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Designed automated reduction application to decreases time for Manual
  Processing ETL. Manual Processing reduced by 16.75%. Tech Stack Java, Oracle, Perl, Azure
  Cloud, Python)
- Completely Designed and Developed Web Applications to enhance multiple portal navigation across the project using Web Frameworks. **Tech Stack React, JavaScript, Python, Azure Cloud, HTML, CSS)**

#### Junior Software Developer, Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai

JUNE 2016 - MAY 2018

- Developed Java Based Application with Oracle Cloud which enhanced operations. Manual Data Processing reduced to 73.5%. As part of Travel & Hospitality unit, developed payment processing to increase traffic among various channels. **Tech Stack Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript**
- Developed and upgraded the existing version of the Mainframe systems to more User Interface design systems with higher computation and less manual processing. Usage of System Resources reduced to 31%. **Tech Stack COBOL, DB2, CICS, Azure Cloud, C++**

# **Education**

## **Ontario Graduate Certificate, Humber College, Toronto**

JANUARY 2021 — SEPTEMBER 2021

Tools Used/Learnt - Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Adobe XD)

Tech Stack - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, Node, Firebase, GraphQL, NextJS, Gatsby

# Post Graduate Ontario Certificate, Fanshawe College, London

JANUARY 2020 — DECEMBER 2020

Graduated with Dean's honors

Tech Stack Used - Java, Selenium, MySQL, Apache JMeter, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Bachelors in Computer Information Technology, Thiagarajar College of Engineering, Madurai

JULY 2012 — MAY 2016